# Kevin L. Miller, Ph.D.

klmille@gmail.com | (310) 562-4572 | Los Angeles, CA 90230

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/kevin-miller-phd-1b197986/ | GitHub: github.com/Koldenblue

**Portfolio:** <a href="https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/">https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

Full-Stack Web Developer with a Ph.D. in chemistry from the University of California, Los Angeles (UCLA). Education in full-stack development from UCLA. Experienced scientific thinker, researcher, and problem-solver. Values community, ethics, integrity, and good business sense, having spent years as a business manager, teacher, and scientist. Extensive teaching experience lends itself to public speaking, leadership, and teamwork skills. Top aim is to contribute to a team while continuously pursuing self-improvement. Seeks to improve the lives of teammates and clients, whether that be in the real world or the digital world.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

- JavaScript/HTML/CSS used as main coding languages. Python as secondary language, with ability and skill to learn further languages.
- Emphasis on MERN stack technologies (MongoDB, Express, React, and Node.js) for front-end and back-end design, database management, routing, and client-server communication
- Research and use of established libraries for streamlining development, such as Redux, jQuery, Handlebars, Sass, and Bootstrap
- SQL database work, through MySQL and the Sequelize Object-Relational Mapper (ORM)
- MongoDB along with Mongoose or mongo.js, for non-relational database management
- Coding techniques include object-oriented programming, asynchronous function handling, mobileresponsive web design, and code testing with tools such as Postman, Jest, and Robo 3T
- AJAX calls for retrieving data from and integrating APIs
- Ability to quickly learn additional libraries for example, React-Spring, Moment.js, or Node Package Manager packages such as Inquirer
- Ability to quickly learn additional programming languages and techniques for example, Python and basic C/C++ programming accomplished through self-study and professional certification

#### **PROJECTS**

• Back-end and front-end coding performed for a wide variety of projects using different technologies. First see portfolio at <a href="https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/">https://kevin-miller-react-portfolio.herokuapp.com/</a>, for full details.

# Color Rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler | https://bit.ly/color-rippler-github

- A solo coded art project that takes advantage of the React and Redux frameworks to efficiently render up to thousands of interactive components in the DOM.
- Combines front-end design with back-end JavaScript algorithms. Data storage and user authentication are accomplished with MongoDB. Node, Express and React provide a back-end framework.

# Express Bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender | https://bit.ly/express-bartender-github

- Executed lead back-end scripting for a small team of coders. Led back-end database design and
  routing design for the team. Programmed storage and updates of user information with SQL
  database.
- Helped teammates solve code difficulties, reviewed team code on GitHub, and contributed to frontend and overall website design.
- Programmed SQL database of drink recipes to cater to authenticated users. Acquired database information using AJAX calls to interact with APIs.

#### **EMPLOYMENT**

# Twinwood, Inc.:

Property Manager and Accountant

October 2013 - August 2020

- Rigorous documentation and coordination of construction projects, with spending in the hundreds of thousands, benefited both tenants and the company through substantial property improvement
- Contributed to business decision making, such as management of over a dozen buildings, and purchasing decisions for properties worth millions
- Meticulous business analytics helped achieve a yearly company growth rate of 3.6% of net worth

#### Praxair:

Lab Technician and Analytical Scientist

October 2014 - February 2015

• Carefully managed lab testing allowed for a fast throughput of dozens of highly pure gasses daily

## University of California, Los Angeles:

Researcher / Teaching Assistant

Sept. 2007 - December 2014

- Intense scientific research led to seven published research papers
- Personal mentoring of two undergraduates helped them publish their own scientific papers
- Chemistry research was awarded Ralph and Charlene Bauer Award, as well as two separate fellowship awards
- Close supervision of hundreds of undergraduate students in both labs and discussion sections, during teaching of over a dozen college-level chemistry discussion courses

# **EDUCATION**

CS50 Professional Certificate - HarvardX Online Full-Stack Web Development Coding Bootcamp - UCLA Extension Ph.D., Chemistry - University of California, Los Angeles B.S., Chemistry - University of California, Irvine